# Yessenia Vieyra

Smithfield, UT 84319 vieyrayessenia8@gmail.com 9132081627

## Summary

I am a motivated individual leader, and driven problem solver who has spent most of my professional life in property management (5 years). Trustworthy in getting tasks done in a timely manner, and willing to learn how to do better. Currently looking for an opportunity to change careers and start my career in the tech world. Recently received my full stack development certificate from the University Of Utah. Ready to apply the skills I have learned and continue to learn more!

#### Skills

- Relationship building and rapport
- Business processes and procedures
- Housing Regulations
- Administrative Regulations
- Budget Preparation
- Cloud based file management
- Multitasking and prioritizing
- Critical thinking

- Javascript
- Front-end programming: CSS & HTML
- Back-end and Database skills
- Databases: Nosql, Sql, MongoDB, Mysql Workbench
- Web & application servers
- Responsive web designs
- User experience design

# Work Experience

## Assistant Property Manager (Full-Time) Kartchner Property Management

(Strata Apartments) - Logan, UT October 2020 to Current

- Collect rent payments monthly and follow up on all delinquencies (past, current, and notice)
- Send accounts to collections and eviction if needed.
- Create renewal offers, negotiate renewal offers if possible and create renewal leases. Complete the move out process from the day notice is given to the determination of deposit refunds or amounts due.
- Schedule appointments throughout the day and be prepared for prospect/resident meetings throughout the day.
- Problem solving resident complaints.
- Assist in leasing when needed such as touring prospective residents, and troubleshooting the application process online.
- Assist with the property manager workload such as reports, property maintenance, and budgeting.
- Manage brand marketing on social media, Apartments.com, Craigslist, and community websites.
- Maintain property occupancy 95% or higher.

Event planning for resident events (resident appreciation).

### Assistant Property Manager/Leasing Consultant (Full-Time) FourSite

Property Management - Kansas City, MO April 2019 to September 2020

- Collect rent payments monthly and follow up on all delinquencies (past, current, and notice) Send accounts to collections and eviction if needed.
- Create renewal offers, negotiate renewal offers if possible and create renewal leases. Complete the move out process from the day notice is given to the determination of deposit refunds or amounts due.
- Schedule all pre-move out inspections and final move out inspections.
- Problem solving resident complaints.
- Assist in leasing when needed such as touring prospective residents and completing an applicant file.
- Process and file away payments made in person in the office.
- Assist with the property manager's work load such as CMA Reports, entering Invoices, bids, weekly reports and approving/denying files when property manager is absent.
- Create payment plans if needed, send reports weekly on delinquencies and send final move out statements for approval to Regional Manager.
- Communicate daily with current and prospective residents as needed to assist with any questions or concerns.
- Help assist in the planning of monthly resident events to show resident appreciation. Assist in the auditing of renewal and application files to ensure that the process has been completed correctly.

## Administrative Assistant/Leasing Consultant (Full-Time)

KC Commercial and Residential Management - Kansas City, MO February 2018 to April 2019

- Billed vendor Invoices.
- Managed utility on and off status for vacant/occupied properties.
- Completed the move in and move out process for past and future residents. •

Payroll for vendors (quick books)

- Data Entry (quick books)
- Experience with Tenant Turner and Appfolio Software.
- Marketing properties on partnered advertisement sites.
- Experience creating work orders for residents.
- Problem solving various complaints from owners and residents.
- Handled lead applications and kept close contact with all leasing agents to manage the application process effectively.
- Experience with high call volume.
- Experience communicating often with leasing leads and owners for leasing updates such as tours and leases.

#### **Quality Assurance Technician (Full-Time)**

Cool Creations - North Kansas City, MO

June 2015 to October 2016

Recorded and inspected factors such as temperature, PH levels, and Chlorine levels that affected the quality production of fruit and vegetable trays.

# Education

# **Full Stack Development Bootcamp**

University of Utah - Utah Current Student

# Associates Of Arts Degree (A.A)

Metropolitan Community College - Kansas City, MO August 2015 to May 2017

# **High school Diploma**

Smith-Cotton High School - Sedalia, MO May 2015